<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Tangents and Timlines</title>
<link>https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/</link>
<atom:link href="https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Tracking hectic weeks and documenting drifting thoughts. A blog built with Quarto</description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.27</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Spring Semester Classes</title>
  <dc:creator>Edwin Kodji</dc:creator>
  <link>https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Spring/Spring Semester Classes.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p><img src="https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Spring/Classes.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>My upcoming classes.</p>
<section id="schedule" class="level1">
<h1>Schedule</h1>
<p>I’ll be taking the following classes this upcoming semester:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>CISC210 (Intro to Systems Programming)</p></li>
<li><p>CPEG202 (Intro to Digital Systems)</p></li>
<li><p>ELEG305 (Signals and Systems)</p></li>
<li><p>HONR290 (Honors Colloqium - Art of Interpretation)</p></li>
<li><p>MATH351 (Engineering Mathematics 1)</p></li>
<li><p>PHYS227 (Fundamentals of Physics Lab 1)</p></li>
<li><p>PHYS228 (Fundamentals of Physics Lab 2)</p></li>
</ul>
<p>One might ask why I’m taking 7 classes next semester. Well, it’s really only five, but the two labs just make it seem like a lot. Also, by doing this, I may be able to graduate a full year early.</p>
<p>I’m still not too sure what I would really like to do in the future (at least, career wise), so taking these classes will give me options in my final few semesters (either a masters degree, or a co-op). That’s my logic at least.</p>
<p>I will definitely have to cut down my hours at work. Maybe I’ll only work for four hours during the weekends. That should be sustainable, but I still do have to curb my procrastination.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Freshman Year</category>
  <category>Spring</category>
  <guid>https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Spring/Spring Semester Classes.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Spring/preview.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>First Semester UD Courses Review</title>
  <dc:creator>Edwin Kodji</dc:creator>
  <link>https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Fall/Fall_Reflection.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>How did my first semester go?</p>
<section id="overview" class="level2" data-number="1">
<h2 data-number="1" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overview"><span class="header-section-number">1</span> Overview</h2>
<p>First year engineering students have common fall semester courses. For this post, I’ll just be detailing my experiences with the classes I had in my first semester.</p>
<div class="alert alert-block alert-info">
<p>Note: Originally, this was supposed to be posted on December 15th, 2025, but I’m incredibly lazy and it’s over a month later that I’m now posting this…</p>
</div>
<p>Section&nbsp;2 Section&nbsp;3 Section&nbsp;4 Section&nbsp;5 Section&nbsp;6 Section&nbsp;7</p>
</section>
<section id="sec-chem103" class="level2" data-number="2">
<h2 data-number="2" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-chem103"><span class="header-section-number">2</span> CHEM103 (B)</h2>
<p>Course Title: General Chemistry</p>
<p>Professor: Dana Chatellier</p>
<p>Rating: 6/10</p>
<p>To be quite honest, I didn’t like this class at all. I took it with Professor Chatellier and the lectures were very dense (or maybe I am). We breezed through High School Chemistry in about 3 weeks or so.</p>
<p>There was a lot of rote memorization, as well as some very annoying topics to learn. I’m looking you, quantum numbers and VSEPR theory.</p>
<p>I also worked as a Cashier on weekends, so that reduced the amount of time I could spend doing homework. Actually, there was no homework for this class. Our professor gave us suggested homework problems, but again, I’m incredibly lazy.</p>
<p>Your grade in this class is solely tied to four exams, each with equal weight (100 points). Your highest score is doubled, however, so there is a total of 500 points you can earn in this class. It’s honestly so easy to pass this class. Getting a 50 on every exam would net you a C-…</p>
<p>My grades on the exams in chronological order are: 88, 84, 78, and… a 60. Yes, I failed the final exam. A lot of people got an A, however. I only needed a %4 on the final to pass with a B, and since it was impossible for me to get an A, you can imagine how much effort I actually put into studying.</p>
<p>With the class average being a 91.5, I honestly think may have used <em>other</em> tools while taking the test. The test was online with no supervision…</p>
<p>If you’re interested, here’s a reddit discussion on this: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/udel/comments/1p5ifkd/mass_cheating_general_chemistry/" class="uri">https://www.reddit.com/r/udel/comments/1p5ifkd/mass_cheating_general_chemistry/</a></p>
</section>
<section id="sec-chem133" class="level2" data-number="3">
<h2 data-number="3" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-chem133"><span class="header-section-number">3</span> CHEM133 (A-)</h2>
<p>Course Title: General Chemistry Laboratory</p>
<p>Professor: Dr.&nbsp;Burke (class is run by TA’s)</p>
<p>Rating: 3/10</p>
<p>The Rate My Professor for Dr.&nbsp;Burke should give you a general idea of what people think about this class.</p>
<p>You’re given a pre-lab which just tests you on concepts that will be used to answer questions after the lab. You’re also expected to write down a lab procedure that you will use throughout the lab session. Afterwards, there are discussion questions to answer.</p>
<p>You’re given two days after the lab to submit your work, but at the end of the semester they will forgive up to 26 hours of late submissions.</p>
<p>Honestly, the main gripe I have about this lab is that the lab manual doesn’t go into enough detail on the concepts needed to answer the discussion questions. I found myself having to try to learn using outside resources, and it doesn’t help that the CHEM103 class is a bit behind the lab.</p>
<p>The grading is also very dependent on the TA grading that week. My grade felt random at times.</p>
<p>I’m quite sure I failed the final for this class too, but you’re not given the chance to view your score. It’s online and you could use your lab manual, but even with that, I wouldn’t be surprised if I scored below 20%. They must have curved everyone’s grades a lot.</p>
</section>
<section id="sec-egg101" class="level2" data-number="4">
<h2 data-number="4" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-egg101"><span class="header-section-number">4</span> EGG101 (A)</h2>
<p>Course Title: Introduction to Engineering</p>
<p>Professor: Dr.&nbsp;Malladi</p>
<p>Rating: 7/10</p>
<p>You can honestly just skip the Monday lecture’s and you’ll still be fine. The lecture slides are posted on Canvas.</p>
<p>The course in of itself isn’t that bad—it’s supposed to be giving you an overview of what engineering is like. There’s a big project with a hard deadline, and it’s all broken up into a few phases.</p>
<p>There’s just a lot of busy work in this class. The reflections were a pain, and there are weekly videos you have to watch in order to answer the questions for an assignment.</p>
<p>I don’t think a board game is a bad idea for the project, but I do wish it were more interesting. Then again, we are all first years and we aren’t expected to have experience.</p>
<p>I had a wonderful group (shoutout to team 333!). Everyone contributed and worked really well. We even got an award!</p>
<p>I do wish I paid more attention in class though. Dr.&nbsp;Malladi is really passionate about what she teaches, and I feel bad for doing computer science homework while she talked. The knowledge of the engineering design process may be useful someday, too.</p>
</section>
<section id="sec-math243" class="level2" data-number="5">
<h2 data-number="5" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-math243"><span class="header-section-number">5</span> MATH243 (A)</h2>
<p>Course Title: Analytic Geometry and Calculus C</p>
<p>Professor: Novi Bong</p>
<p>Rating: 9/10</p>
<p>Professor Bong is amazing! Her explanations are really clear, and she’s super relatable too! She does take attendance, but not always.</p>
<p>You also get an extra 10% on your homework for submitting it early, so that can help your grade if you really need it.</p>
<p>I didn’t find the class all that difficult. If you do the homework and pay attention in class, you’ll be fine. There are pop quizzes, but those weren’t terribly difficult.</p>
<p>I started skipping the discussion sessions because I had to pick up my brother from school, but I still somehow got a very high participation grade.</p>
<p>I also kept on asking dumb questions in those sessions, and I was really embarrassed. That probably plays a role in why I started skipping class too.</p>
</section>
<section id="sec-cisc106" class="level2" data-number="6">
<h2 data-number="6" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-cisc106"><span class="header-section-number">6</span> CISC106 (A)</h2>
<p>Course Title: General Computer Science for Engineers (Honors)</p>
<p>Professor: Nazim Karaca</p>
<p>Rating: 7/10</p>
<p>To be quite honest, this course is self taught. Going to lecture felt pointless because well, I didn’t really gain much from them. Professor Nazim is interesting, but I didn’t really get to know him all that well.</p>
<p>The lab sessions (practicums) felt especially useless. I really didn’t gain anything from them, especially since the course is largely self taught.</p>
<p>I started skipping class after a while and started not doing some of the assignments. That actually hurt my grade quite a bit, but I still ended up doing well.</p>
<p>The exams <em>felt</em> fairly easy, but exam 2 was notoriously difficult. I don’t know anyone who managed to get the last question.</p>
<p>Maybe this class was easier for me because I have prior programming experience because I know many people struggled. I would often try to speed run the homework, but there were a few that tripped me up for a while.</p>
<p>The Honors Hackathon was really fun though! I believe that this was the first year they hosted it and I wonder if they’ll do it again. There were a lot of interesting projects made. See the post below for a little more information</p>
<p><a href="../../../posts/Freshman Year/Fall/Hackathon.html">Honors Hackathon</a></p>
</section>
<section id="sec-engl110" class="level2" data-number="7">
<h2 data-number="7" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-engl110"><span class="header-section-number">7</span> ENGL110 (A)</h2>
<p>Course Title: First Year Writing (Honors)</p>
<p>Professor: Dr.&nbsp;Wilson</p>
<p>Rating: 9/10</p>
<p>This class was very interesting. It’s a first year class with a theme on trauma. I gained so much knowledge and I recommend anyone who has the chance to take this class to make use of the opportunity.</p>
<p>Dr.&nbsp;Wilson is so intelligent, funny, and really interesting. I should mention that at times she does derail off the material we are supposed to be learning, but even then, those tangents are really informative.</p>
<p>She gives a decent amount of extra credit through extra lectures and the banned books read aloud.</p>
<p>There is a good amount of reading in this class, but that’s only at the start of the semester. As the semester goes on, there isn’t so much reading, but you do have to do research for your research paper.</p>
<p>I really, really liked this class. This is coming from someone who doesn’t really like taking English classes. I hope to take another class with her at some point.</p>
<hr>
<p>Well, that’s the end of the post. My first semester was fairly interesting, and I learned quite a bit! Upon reflecting, I skipped quite a few classes, huh? It all worked out in the end though. Take a look at my next semester classes here:<br>
<br>
<a href="../../../posts/Freshman Year/Spring/Spring Semester Classes.html">Spring Semester Classes</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Freshman Year</category>
  <category>Fall</category>
  <guid>https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Fall/Fall_Reflection.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Fall/Arches.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Honors Hackathon</title>
  <dc:creator>Edwin Kodji</dc:creator>
  <link>https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Fall/Hackathon.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<p>My first post!</p>
<section id="introduction" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Hi! I guess this is the first blog post, huh? I hope to journal about my college experience so that I can later on look back upon it. I was thinking of writing everyday, but I’ve realized that’ll probably be very difficult. We’ll see, I guess.</p>
<p>Anyways—the Honors Hackathon! I’ve never participated in a Hackathon before. The best I can compare it to is the Big Ideas Challenge me and my engineering group participated in yesterday and a game jam I took part of in 8th grade.</p>
<p>Speaking of the Big Ideas Challenge, we didn’t win, but it was still really interesting to see what other people have created. I wish I took pictures.</p>
<p>I’ll try to take pictures while I’m at the Hackathon though. I wonder what it’s like… they don’t tell you what to make, so it’s simply up to you and your partner’s imagination. Now that I think of it, I don’t know many people who did sign up for the Hackathon. Ah well, maybe I’ll try to rope someone into working with me. Two heads are better than one, after all.</p>
<p>I’m not very good at programming, but I hope to do somewhat well.</p>
</section>
<section id="post-hackathon" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="post-hackathon">Post Hackathon</h2>
<p>You won’t believe it, but I <strong>WON</strong>! I essentially made a Terms and Conditions reader using the Google Gemini API. You can paste in some Terms and Conditions from YouTube, let’s say, and it’ll tell you a brief breakdown of the policies the site has. Gemini’s API was really frustrating to use, and I almost scrapped my idea a few hours in.</p>
<p>I leaked my API key towards the end of the challenge… that was really scary. I think Dr.&nbsp;Bart was talking about how people in other Hackathons exposed their API keys as well and warned us about it.</p>
<p>If you’d like to try out my site, here’s the link: <a href="https://edwinko-alt.github.io/Fine-Print-Buster/" class="uri">https://edwinko-alt.github.io/Fine-Print-Buster/</a></p>
<p>I do hope it’s still up. I ran into some CloudFlare issues when setting it up, but everything should work now.</p>
<p>Just wait a few moments after hitting ‘send’ because it takes a while for everything to work.</p>
<p>Wow, I honestly can’t believe that I won… I thought that there were some very impressive projects that were much more impressive and useful that what I made. Well, regardless, I now have an iPad to show for it. I’m really glad that I went.</p>
<p>I wish I took pictures… I was supposed to, but working on the site took up so much of my time. I also wish I could’ve worked with someone else. That would have been a lot more fun.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Freshman Year</category>
  <category>Fall</category>
  <guid>https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Fall/Hackathon.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://edwinkio.github.io/Tangents_and_Timelines/posts/Freshman Year/Fall/hackathon.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="81" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
